# Yenchin Lai

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen E-mail: ylai@uni-bremen.de

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research during master's program is focused on human behavior, cognition, and emotion in the field of human-computer interaction. In my master's thesis, I create a face interaction system based on empirical studies. Currently, I am focusing on affective computing, positive computing and wearable interaction in my PhD research.

## **EDUCATION**

### PhD Candidate in Computer Science

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany Affective Computing and Experience Design

## Master's Degree in Media Design

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan User-Defined Face Gesture Interactions Using Webcams

#### Language Interpretation

Japan College of Foreign Languages, Tokyo, Japan

#### Bachelor's Degree in Education

Department of Human Development and Family Studies, National Taiwan Normal University With extra-curricular credits at B.F.A Degree Program in Performing Arts

## ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

2019-present Researcher

Digital Media Lab, University of Bremen, Germany Graduate School "Empowering Digital Media" funded by Klaus Tschira Foundation

#### Research Assistant

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan Research Assistant in Geist project

2016-2018

2019-present

2015-2016

2010-2014

2018

## Teaching Assistant

2017-2018

Graduate School of Media Design, Keio University of Japan

Workshop Assistant in KMD Crash Course and Studio Assistant of Network Studio

### Research Program Participant

2016-2017

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

JST CREST, Research Topic: "Behavior change and harmonious collaboration by experiential supplements"

#### **Student Innovation Contest**

2016

ACM UIST 2016 Student Innovation Contest

"Most Creative Interface honorable mention" with our work "Facecook"

#### **Exchange Program**

2014

Osaka Prefecture University of Japan

An one-semester program studying in Humanities and Social Sciences and participation in seminars on the topic of Human Sexuality and Gender

## Practicum 2013

Public Zhong Xin Daycare Center, New Taipei City, Taiwan Course credits for Practicum in Early Childhood Education

## INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance Translator and Interpreter

2012-2018

Japanese-Chinese-English Language Translation and Interpretation

Working mostly with companies and agencies related to music, entertainment, cultures, and design

### Student Volunteer

2017

Unite 2017 Tokyo

Student volunteer for Unite 2017 Tokyo held by Unity Technologies

## Hackathon 2016-2017

Live Music Hackasong

A 3-month hackathon focusing on the idea of combining live performance and technology to create brand new live experiences held by Billboard Japan and Contents Innovation Program.

### Game Music Design

2010-2011

"Crazy Festival" and "hielo store"

Music and sound design for Taiwanese phone games

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Yenchin Lai, Benjamin Tag, Kai Kunze, Rainer Malaka. 2020. Understanding Face Gestures with a User-Centered Approach Using Personal Computer Applications as an Example. In AHs '20: Augmented Humans International Conference (AHs '20). ACM, Kaiserslautern, Germany.

Lai Yen-Chin, YuanLing Feng, Kai Kunze, Junich Shimizu, and Takuro Nakao. Eyewear to Make Me Smile: Can Electric Muscle Stimulation increase Happiness? In Proceedings of the Eleventh International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction (TEI'17). ACM, Yokohama, Japan.

George Chernyshov, Jiajun Chen, **Yenchin Lai**, Vontin Noriyasu, and Kai Kunze. *Ambient Rhythm: Melodic Sonification of Status Information for IoT-enabled Devices*. In Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on the Internet of Things (IoT'16). ACM, Stuttgart, Germany.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, C#, HTML, Arduino, LATEX

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Chinese Native Speaker English Fluent, TOEIC: 815

Japanese Fluent, JLPT: N1, BJT: J1+